(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
2021 12/27 21:00 3D LIVE
天音かなた2周年記念 REVENGE
Amane Kanata 2nd Anniversary: REVENGE
魂の色は
What color is
何色ですか
your soul?
ANIMA
作詞：毛蟹(LIVE LAB.) 作曲：毛蟹(LIVE LAB.)
Lyrics: Kegani (LIVE LAB.) Composition: Kegani (LIVE LAB.)
「もういい」って 折れたままで
Saying "Enough", while staying broken,
捨てるほど
not strong enough to
逃げ出すほど
throw it away or run away,
強くないよ ほら
you see.
もう一度 鼓動、高鳴る
Once more, my heartbeat quickens.
何が正しいかなんて
I don't know what's right,
わからないけど
but...
形のないものばかりが
Only things without a shape
大切になっていく
are becoming important.
飾らない言葉だけが
Only unadorned words
強く結ばれてる
are strongly tied together.
また躓いて 転がって
Stumbling again, rolling,
それでも砕けない
and yet I won't break.
魂の色は
What color is
何色ですか
your soul?
叩きつけて 強がって
Striking down, acting tough,
それでも見つけたいよ
and yet I want to find it.
魂のカタチ
I'm confirming the shape
確かめてるよ
of my soul.
深い地の底で一人
Alone in the deep depths of the earth,
扉と鍵を探す
searching for the door and the key.
お伽話は ほら
Fairytales, you see,
泡の様に全部消えて
all vanish like bubbles,
葛藤、残像だけ
leaving only conflict and afterimages.
次のページへ
To the next page.
伸びていく枝葉が分かれて
The growing branches separate,
それぞれの道を行く
and each goes its own way.
寂しい思い出だけが
Only lonely memories
強く根を張ってる
are strongly taking root.
まだ貫いて 失って
Still piercing through, losing,
それでも挫けない
and yet I won't be discouraged.
心はどこに
Where is the heart?
器はどこに
Where is the vessel?
ただ残されて 抜け落ちて
Just left behind, falling out,
それでも伝えたいよ
and yet I want to convey it.
魂の日々を
The days of my soul,
魂の意志を
the will of my soul.
ずっと
Forever.
魂の色は
The color of the soul is...
何色ですか
What color is it?
赤色ですか
Is it red?
青色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
The color of the soul is...
何色ですか
What color is it?
透明な過去に
To a transparent past
不透明な明日に
To an opaque tomorrow
生きるあなたは
You who lives
何色ですか
What color are you?
また躓いて
Tripping again
転がって
Rolling over
それでも砕けない
Yet still not breaking
魂の色は
The color of the soul is...
何色ですか
What color is it?
ただ傷ついて
Just getting hurt
強がって
Acting tough
それでも見つけたいよ
I still want to find it
魂のカタチ
The shape of the soul
確かめてるよ
I'm making sure
ずっと... (Woah...)
Forever... (Woah...)
AMANE KANATA REVENGE
Woah...
半端なら K.O.
Half-hearted means K.O.
今宵は...
Tonight...
Hey! Hey! Yeah! Yeah!
なんだかってつまんない
Something's just boring
こともあるでしょう
There must be things like that
ロンリー論理のノート
Lonely logic notebook
ハンディー本気疾走
Handy serious sprint
やんちゃっちゃって泥に
Being mischievous in the mud
Bad ご法度なロゴが
Bad forbidden logo
溺れて堕ちて
Drowning and falling
そろそろいっか
Is it about time?
もっと頑張って
Work harder
アガるまでもっと頑張って
Work harder until you're pumped
繋がろう独りよりふたり
Let's connect, two rather than one
増えたら安心心配ないや
More people means peace of mind, no worries
Alright 任せて Don't Mind
Alright, leave it to me, Don't Mind
波あり難題みんなで乗っちゃえば
Waves and challenges, let's all ride them
案外まく行ったりしそう
It might actually go surprisingly well
じゃいそう？じゃいそう！
Will it? It will!
半端なら K.O.
Half-hearted means K.O.
ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
If you want to feel lightheaded, go ahead
開演準備しちゃおうか
Shall we get ready for the show?
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Love me whether I cry or laugh
ほら Say No 低音響かせろ
Look, Say No, let the bass resonate
Woah...
今宵は暗転パーティー
Tonight is a blackout party
Woah...
踊り出せ 踊り出せ
Start dancing, start dancing
孤独は殺菌 満員御礼
Sterilize loneliness, a full house
Woah...
痛みまでおシェアで
Sharing even the pain
心でバイバイ Let go
Goodbye in my heart, Let go
どんな劣等感だって
Whatever inferiority complex you have
即興の血小板で
With improvised platelets
抑え込んで 突っ込んで 仕舞っちゃうでしょ
Suppress it, push into it, and put it away
Up and down テンション
Up and down tension
ねえまいっちゃってんの相当
Hey, you're pretty overwhelmed
ドバっと噴き出すのは
What bursts out
本音の独り言
Is a monologue of true feelings
別に興味ない
I'm not particularly interested
特に関係ない
It doesn't particularly matter
塞ぎ込んで 舌鋒鋭へ
Feeling down, sharpening the tongue
合図を奏でて Bra-bra-bra-player
Play the signal, Bra-bra-bra-player
ほら集まって夜行行脚 Yeah
Look, gather round, nocturnal pilgrimage Yeah
鳴いていよう
Let's keep singing
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
サクッと行っちゃいそう
It feels like it'll go smoothly
Woah...
踊り出せ 踊り出せ
Start dancing, start dancing
孤独は殺菌 満員御礼
Sterilize loneliness, a full house
Woah...
痛みまでおシェアで
Sharing even the pain
今宵も暗転パーティーだ
Tonight is a blackout party again
Woah... (Woah...)
またのお越しを きっと
Come back again, surely
Woah...
次回までお元気で
Stay well until next time
心でバイバイ Let go
Goodbye in my heart, Let go
Woah...
Hey! Hey! Hey!
ここでバイバイ Let go
Goodbye here, Let go
胸ぐらを掴まれて
Getting grabbed by the collar
強烈なパンチを
A heavy punch
食らってよろけて
Taking it and staggering
肩を並べ蹲った
Squatting side by side
予報通りの雨に
In the rain that was forecast
お前はニヤけて
You smirked
予報通りの雨　お前に射されて
Rain just as predicted, I'm struck by you
「傷口が綺麗に映る」　なんて嘘をつく
"Wounds look beautiful," you lie to me
いつも口喧嘩さえ
Even though you're no good
上手く出来ないくせして
at having a simple argument
冴えない冗談言うなよ
Don't tell those lame jokes
あまりのつまらなさに目が潤んだ
My eyes welled up because it was so boring
何度も　青アザだらけで涙を
Time and again, covered in bruises, shedding tears
流して流して
on and on
不安定な心を
Resting our unstable hearts
肩に預け合いながら
on each other's shoulders
腐り切ったバッドエンドに抗う
Resisting this rotten bad end
なぜだろう　喜びよりも心地よい
I wonder why, it feels better than joy
痛み　ずっしりと響いて
This heavy pain resonating within
濡れた服に　舌打ちしながら
Clicking our tongues at wet clothes
腫れ上がった顔見合って笑う
we look at our swollen faces and laugh
土砂降りの夜に
On a night of downpouring rain
誓ったリベンジ
The revenge we swore
胸ぐらを掴み返して
Grab them by the collar
反撃のパンチを
and throw a counter punch
繰り出すくらいじゃなきゃ
If I can't do at least that
お前の隣には立てないから
I can't stand by your side
相手が何であれ日和らない
No matter who the opponent is, don't waver
何度負かされても諦めない
don't give up even if defeated
忘れるな　忘れるなと
Don't forget, don't forget
言い聞かせ続けてたのに
I kept telling myself
どうして...
Why...?
傘はいらないから
I don't need an umbrella
言葉を一つ作らないか
so shall we create a single word?
微温い優しさではなく
Not a lukewarm kindness
弱音に侵された胸の奥を
but a word that carves into the depth
抉るような言葉を
of a heart invaded by weakness
何度も　青アザだらけで涙を
Time and again, covered in bruises, shedding tears
流して流して
on and on
不安定な心を
Resting our unstable hearts
肩に預け合いながら
on each other's shoulders
腐り切ったバッドエンドに抗う
Resisting this rotten bad end
なぜだろう　喜びよりも心地よい
I wonder why, it feels better than joy
痛み　ずっしりと響いて
This heavy pain resonating within
濡れた服に　舌打ちしながら
Clicking our tongues at wet clothes
腫れ上がった顔見合って笑う
we look at our swollen faces and laugh
土砂降りの夜に
On a night of downpouring rain
誓ったリベンジ
The revenge we swore
土砂降りの夜に
On a night of downpouring rain
囚われの日々に
In the days of being trapped
問いかけるように
As if questioning
光った瞳の中で
within those shining eyes
誓ったリベンジ
The revenge we swore
深夜東京の6畳半　夢を見てた
In a six-and-a-half mat room in late-night Tokyo, I was dreaming
灯りの灯らない蛍光灯
Unlit fluorescent lights
明日には消えてる電脳城に
in a cyber castle that will be gone by tomorrow
開幕戦打ち上げて　いかなくちゃないよね
I have to launch the opening battle and go, don't I?
ここには誰もいない
No one is here
ここには誰もいないから
because no one is here
春を告げる
Haru wo Tsugeru
ここに救いはないよ
There is no salvation here
早く行っておいでおいで
go on, go quickly
難しい話はやめよう
Let's stop the difficult talk
とりあえず上がって酒でも飲んでさ
for now just come up and have a drink
いつも誰にでも言っていることを
Saying the same thing you always say to everyone
繰り返してる
Repeating it
完璧な演出と
A perfect performance and
完璧な人生を
a perfect life
幼少期の面影は誰も知らないんだ
No one knows the traces of childhood
誰もがマイノリティなタイムトラベラー
Everyone is a minority time traveler
ほら真夜中はすぐそこさ
look, midnight is right there
さあ
Now
深夜東京の6畳半　夢を見てた
In a six-and-a-half mat room in late-night Tokyo, I was dreaming
灯りの灯らない蛍光灯
Unlit fluorescent lights
明日には消えてる電脳城に
in a cyber castle that will be gone by tomorrow
開幕戦打ち上げて　いかなくちゃないよね
I have to launch the opening battle and go, don't I?
ここには誰もいない
No one is here
明日世界は終わるんだって 昨日は眠れなくて
"I heard the world ends tomorrow," I couldn't sleep last night.
あぁ 小さな記憶の箱は 夜の海に浮かんでる
Ah, a small box of memories floats on the night sea.
僕らを描いたあの絵の中に 吸い込まれるように
As if being sucked into that painting that depicted us.
週末旅行を楽しもう
Let's enjoy our weekend voyage,
どうせ全部今日で終わるんだから
since everything ends today anyway.
深夜東京の6畳半
In a 6-tatami room in late-night Tokyo,
夢を見ていた
I was dreaming.
灯りの灯らない蛍光灯
Fluorescent lights that don't turn on,
明日には消えてる電脳城に
in the cyber castle that will vanish tomorrow.
開幕戦打ち上げて いなくなんないよね
Setting off the opening battle, you won't disappear, right?
ここには誰もいない ここには誰もいない
No one is here. No one is here.
深夜東京の6畳半 夢を見ていた
In a 6-tatami room in late-night Tokyo, I was dreaming.
灯りの灯らない蛍光灯 明日には消えてる電脳城に
Fluorescent lights that don't turn on, in the cyber castle that will vanish tomorrow.
開幕戦打ち上げて いなくなんないよね
Setting off the opening battle, you won't disappear, right?
ここには誰もいない ここには誰もいないから
Because no one is here. Because no one is here.
Party is over.
それでも踊りたかった
Even so, I wanted to dance.
眠れないくらい
Enough to keep me from sleeping.
情熱の火はいつしか いつの日にか
The fire of passion will, before I know it, someday...
はなから気付いている
I've known from the start,
焔はいつか消える
the flame will one day go out.
ねぇ 何も要らないはずだったのに
Hey, I wasn't supposed to need anything,
まだ I'm so serious
but I'm still so serious.
あぁ あぁ 間に合う
Ah, ah, I'll make it in time.
Burn it up.
Baby, Sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ
Baby, Sorry darling, it's not that sweet.
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But I'm sure it's not that bad.
Give me fire.
Light it up Baby 燃やしちゃおうぜ yeah
Light it up Baby, let's burn it up, yeah.
火炎
作詞：薔薇園アヴ 作曲：薔薇園アヴ
FIRE
Lyrics: Barazono Avu Composition: Barazono Avu
燃えろよ 燃えろよ 炎よ 燃えろ
Burn, burn, o flame, burn.
千代も八千代も 変わりもせずに
For thousands of ages, without changing.
人のなりとかし全部 燃やせや ああ よしよし
Melting all human form, burn it all, ah, there there.
出でよ 舞えよ 火の粉 焚き付けるのが仕事
Come forth, dance, sparks, fanning the flames is the job.
ガソリンとステロイド 燃える様はお見事
Gasoline and steroids, the way it burns is magnificent.
火遊びはしない ぬるい真似はしない
No playing with fire, no lukewarm acting.
無理、しけた火を ドラマ 燃やし尽くす マグマ ドラマ
Impossible, a damp fire, drama, burning everything up, magma drama.
この飽くなき渇き 青い炎みたい
This insatiable thirst, like a blue flame.
死はひとつ隣 やがて総てひとつ隣
Death is right next to you, soon everything will be right next to it.
Love is dying.
でもまだ消えてないから
But it hasn't gone out yet.
忘れてみたい
I want to try and forget.
情熱の火はいつしか いつの日にか
The fire of passion will, before I know it, someday...
身体は気付いている 僕らはいつか消える
My body realizes, we will one day disappear.
ゆるやかに若さを溶かして
Gently melting away youth,
泣かないで Why so serious?
don't cry, Why so serious?
あぁ あぁ 間に合う
Ah, ah, I'll make it in time.
Burn it up.
Baby, Sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ
Baby, Sorry darling, it's not that sweet.
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But I'm sure it's not that bad.
Give me fire.
Light it up Baby 燃やしちゃおうぜ yeah
Light it up Baby, let's burn it up, yeah.
Turn it up…足りない 注ぐ火に油！
Turn it up… Not enough, pour oil on the fire!
Sorry darling Hurry up ああまだ間に合う？
Sorry darling Hurry up, ah is it still in time?
Sorry darling Hurry up あなたが Burn it up
Sorry darling Hurry up, you burn it up
Give me fire
Light it up Baby 燃やしちゃおうぜ yeah
Light it up Baby, let's burn it up yeah
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
Still, I wanted to dance
現る黒い空
A black sky appears
鼓動は雷鳴を繰り返す
My heartbeat repeats the thunder
嵐がくる前に
Before the storm comes
今宵は あの歌を授けましょう
Tonight, let me grant you that song
マハリ ユフレ ガアイェ サヴァァナレ
Mahari Yufure Gaaie Savannahre
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ カナシャラ
Amare Dirahi Jumagi Kanashara
マハリ ユフレ ガアイェ サヴァァナレ
Mahari Yufure Gaaie Savannahre
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ カナシャラ
Amare Dirahi Jumagi Kanashara
覚醒
Awakening
蘇らせるのさ
I'll bring it back to life
愛する君の心
Your heart that I love
身体を脱ぎ捨てて
Cast off your body
今 我に還るとき
Now is the time to return to yourself
マハリ ユフレ ガアイェ サヴァァナレ
Mahari Yufure Gaaie Savannahre
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ カナシャラ
Amare Dirahi Jumagi Kanashara
マハリ ユフレ ガアイェ サヴァァナレ
Mahari Yufure Gaaie Savannahre
天に吠えて 覚醒
Howl at the heavens, awakening
目をつぶって
Close your eyes
風をすくって
Scoop up the wind
身を溶かして
Melt your body
鐘を鳴らして
Ring the bell
マハリ ユフレ ガアイェ サヴァァナレ
Mahari Yufure Gaaie Savannahre
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ カナシャラ
Amare Dirahi Jumagi Kanashara
マハリ ユフレ ガアイェ サヴァァナレ
Mahari Yufure Gaaie Savannahre
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ カナシャラ
Amare Dirahi Jumagi Kanashara
マハリ ユフレ ガアイェ サヴァァナレ
Mahari Yufure Gaaie Savannahre
アマレ ディラヒ ジュマギ カナシャラ
Amare Dirahi Jumagi Kanashara
マハリ ユフレ ガアイェ サヴァァナレ
Mahari Yufure Gaaie Savannahre
天に吠えて 覚醒
Howl at the heavens, awakening
雷鳴は
The thunder
何度もうぶごえをあげる
Will cry out again and again
ウタのサマ
The state of the song
闇を越えて 飛び出せ
Go beyond the darkness and soar
マハリ ユフレ ガアイェ サヴァァナレ…
Mahari Yufure Gaaie Savannahre...
特報
Special Report
作詞 作曲
Lyrics / Composition
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
編曲
Arrangement
Numa
代表作：「廻廻奇譚」「ドラマツルギー」「アウトサイダー」
Notable works: "Kaikai Kitan", "Dramaturgy", "Outsider"
オリジナル曲 制作決定
Original Song Production Decided
有象無象 人の成り 虚勢 心象 人外 物の怪みたいだ
Various people, in human form, bluffs, mental images, like monsters.
虚心坦懐 命宿し あとはぱっぱらぱんな中身なき人間
Open-hearted, life dwells within, then it's just empty humans.
寄せる期待 不平等な人生 才能もない 大抵 非日常が
Expectations gather, an unequal life, no talent, mostly the extraordinary...
怨親平等に没個性 辿る記憶 僕に居場所などないから
Impartial to friends and foes, losing individuality, tracing memories, for I have no place.
夢の狭間で泣いてないで どんな顔すればいいか分かってる
Don't cry in the gap between dreams, I know what kind of face I should make.
だけどまだ応えてくれよ
But please, still answer me.
闇を祓って 闇を祓って 夜の帳が下りたら合図だ
Exorcise the darkness, exorcise the darkness, it's the signal when night falls.
相対して 廻る環状線 戯言などは 吐き捨ていけと
Facing each other, the revolving loop, cast aside all the nonsense and go.
まだ止めないで まだ止めないで 誰よりも聡く在る街に生まれし
Don't stop yet, don't stop yet, born in a city that's smarter than anyone.
この正体を 今はただ 呪い呪われた僕の未来を創造して
This identity, for now, just create the future of my cursed self.
走って 転んで 消えない痛み抱いては
Running, falling, embracing the pain that won't fade.
世界が待ってる この一瞬を
The world is waiting for this moment.
叙情的感情が揺らいでいくバグ 従順に従った欠陥の罰
A bug where emotions waver, the punishment of a flaw that followed obediently.
死守選択しかない愛に無常気 声も出せないまま
Indifferent to love with only a choice to defend, unable to make a sound.
傀儡な誓いの街百鬼夜行 数珠繋ぎなこの果てまでも
Night parade in a city of puppet oaths, even to this linked end.
極楽往生 現実蹴って 命を投げ出さないで
Rebirth in paradise, kicking reality, don't throw your life away.
内の脆さに浸って どんな顔すればいいか分かんないよ
Immersed in internal fragility, I don't know what face I should make.
今はただ応えてくれよ
For now, just answer me.
五常を解いて 五常を解いて 不確かな声を紡ぐイデア
Unravel the constants, unravel the constants, the idea that weaves uncertain voices.
相殺して 廻る感情線 その先に今 立ち上がる手を
Offsetting, the revolving line of emotion, to the hand that rises up now.
ただ追いかけて ただ追いかけて 誰よりも強く在りたいと願う
Just chasing, just chasing, wishing to be stronger than anyone.
君の運命すら 今はただ 仄暗い夜の底に深く深く落ち込んで
Even your fate, for now, just sinking deep into the bottom of the dim night.
不格好に見えたかい これが今の僕なんだ
Did I look unsightly? This is who I am now.
何者にもなれやしないだけの 屍を嗤えよ
Sneer at the corpse that just can't become anything.
目の前の全てから 逃げることさえやめた
I've even stopped running away from everything in front of me.
イメージを繰り返し 想像の先をいけと
Repeating images, tell me to go beyond imagination.
闇を祓って 闇を祓って 夜の帳が下りたら合図だ
Exorcise the darkness, exorcise the darkness, it's the signal when night falls.
相対して 廻る環状線 戯言などは 吐き捨ていけと
Facing each other, the revolving loop, cast aside all the nonsense and go.
まだ止めないで まだ止めないで 誰よりも聡く在る街に生まれし
Don't stop yet, don't stop yet, born in a city that's smarter than anyone.
この正体を 今はただ 呪い呪われた僕の未来を創造して
This identity, for now, just create the future of my cursed self.
走って 転んで 消えない痛み抱いては
Running, falling, embracing the pain that won't fade.
世界が待ってる この一瞬を
The world is waiting for this moment.
嗚呼、いつもの様に 過ぎる日々に あくびが出る
Ah, yawning at the days passing by as usual.
さんざめく夜、越え 今日も 渋谷の街に朝が降る
Crossing the bustling night, morning falls on Shibuya again today.
どこか虚しいような そんな気持ち
A feeling that is somehow empty.
つまらないな
How boring.
でもそれでいい そんなもんさ これでいい
But that's fine. That's just how it is. This is fine.
(知らず知らず隠してた) (本当の声を響かせてよ、ほら)
(Hidden away without knowing) (Let your true voice ring out, look)
(見ないフリしていたっても) (確かにそこに居る)
(Even if you pretend not to see) (It's definitely there)
（見ないフリしていても）
（確かにはそこにある）
(Even if I pretend not to see it)
(It is definitely there)
嗚呼 感じたままに描く
自分で選んだその色で
Ah, I'll draw it as I feel
With the colors I've chosen for myself
眠い空気纏う朝に 訪れた青い世界
In the morning clad in sleepy air, a blue world arrived
好きなものを好きだと言う
怖くて仕方ないけど
Saying I like what I like
I can't help but be afraid
本当の自分出会えた気がしたんだ
I felt like I finally met my true self
嗚呼、手を伸ばせば 伸ばすほどに 遠くへゆく
Ah, the more I reach out my hand, the further it goes
思うようにいかない今日も また慌ただしくもがいてる
Today doesn't go as I thought, I'm struggling frantically again
悔しい気持ちもただ 情けなくて 涙が出る
Even this frustrating feeling, just so pathetic, tears come out
踏み込むほど 苦しくなる 痛くもなる
The more I step in, the more painful and agonizing it becomes
嗚呼 感じたままに進む 自分で選んだこの道を
Ah, I'll move forward as I feel, on this path I've chosen for myself
重い目蓋擦る夜に しがみついた青い誓い
In the night rubbing heavy eyelids, I clung to a blue oath
好きなことを続けること それは楽しいだけじゃない
Continuing to do what I love, it's not just about fun
本当にできる？ 不安になるけど
Can I really do it? I get anxious, but...
何回でも ほら何回でも 自信がないから描いてきたんだよ
Again and again, look, again and again, I've drawn because I lacked confidence
何回でも ほら何回でも 積み上げてきたことが武器になる
Again and again, look, again and again, what I've built up will become my weapon
周りを見たって 誰と比べたって 僕にしかできないことはあんだ
Even if I look around, even if I compare with others, there are things only I can do
今でも 自信なんかない それでも
Even now, I don't have any confidence, but still...
感じたことない気持ち 知らずにいた想い
Feelings I've never felt, thoughts I didn't know I had
あの日踏み出して 初めて感じたこの痛みも全部
Stepping out that day, even all this pain I felt for the first time
好きなものと向き合うことで 触れたまだ小さな光
By facing what I like, I touched a light that's still small
大丈夫、行こう あとは楽しむだけだ
It's okay, let's go. All that's left is to enjoy it
嗚呼 全てを賭けて描く 自分にしか出せない色で
Ah, I'll draw by betting everything, with colors only I can produce
朝も夜も走り続け 見つけ出した青い光
Running through both morning and night, I found the blue light
好きなものと向き合うこと 今だって怖いことだけど
Facing what I like, even now it's a scary thing, but...
もう今は あの日の透明な僕じゃない
I'm no longer that transparent version of myself from that day
嗚呼 ありのままの かけがえのない僕だ
Ah, I'm just as I am, irreplaceable
（知らず知らず隠してた）
（本当の声を響かせてよ ほら）
(I was hiding it without knowing)
(Let your true voice resound, look)
（見ないフリしていても）
（確かにはそこには今もそこにある）
(Even if you pretend not to see it)
(It is definitely there, still there now)
（知らず知らず隠してた）
（本当の声を響かせてよ さあ）
(I was hiding it without knowing)
(Let your true voice resound, come on)
（見ないフリしていても）
（確かにはそこに君の中に）
(Even if you pretend not to see it)
(It is definitely there, inside you)
Don't take your love away.
You ain't heard nothin' yet-yet.
Wake up, make up, bang bang.
また鳴り出した表示はあなた「今、忙しいの」
The display started ringing again, it's you. "I'm busy right now."
[A]ddiction feat.Mori Calliope
未読のトークとラブコールも
いっぱいでせわしない「邪魔をしないで頂戴」
Unread chats and love calls,
it's too much and busy. "Please don't disturb me."
Cuz you refuse cooperation, better stick out your lip
Too used to sayin' "I don't wanna",
no doubt you're still a kid
本音は言わない方が悩ましい
It's more troublesome not to say what you're really thinking
甘い言葉かけるよりもずっと愛しい
Far more lovely than saying sweet words
たまらなく欲するほど 求めて離さないで
So much that it's unbearable, seek me and don't let go
キスじゃ足りなくて いっそ殺して
A kiss isn't enough, just kill me instead
Predilection あなたを手に掛けて
Predilection, getting my hands on you
Infatuation 呼吸さえ止めて
Infatuation, even stopping my breath
Dedication このまま
Dedication, just like this
Addiction してまだたった一口で「終わり」
Addiction, and yet just one taste and it's over
Predilection さあ口をつけて
Predilection, now put your mouth to it
Infatuation そのまま飲み込んで
Infatuation, just swallow it as is
Dedication すぐさま
Dedication, immediately
Addiction してほらたった一口
死ぬほど愛したいから
Addiction, look, just one taste
Because I want to love you to death
Don't take your love away.
You ain't heard nothin' yet-yet.
Wake up, make up, bang bang.
Uh, have it all, like it love is overflowing
Be the only one you got, I don't think you'll be going, going
Uh, take it off, still it's not enough for me
Stuck. With. You. There's no room for other things.
胸を刺したこの手掴んだ
I grasped this hand that pierced my chest,
まだ未練があるのね
You still have lingering regrets, don't you?
ああまただわ
Ah, there it goes again,
ワガママ
Your selfishness.
愛と名付けてまた支配する
Naming it love, you dominate once more.
あなたに溺れてく
I'm drowning in you,
息苦しいくらいに
To the point of suffocation.
心酔させていっそうして
Mesmerize me, even more so.
Predilection
わたしを手に掛けて
Lay your hands on me
Infatuation
キスで口塞いで
Seal my lips with a kiss
Dedication
まだまだ
Not yet, not yet
Addiction
してまた雑多、非合理的な愛
And again, a cluttered, irrational love.
Predilection
喉奥流し込んで
Pour it down my throat
Infatuation
躊躇いなど捨てて
Throw away all hesitation
Dedication
すぐさま
Immediately
Addiction
してほらたった一口 これで終わらせないで
See, just one mouthful. Don't let it end here.
Our love's, love's continue to further evolve more.
My love love is besotted with you.
You love? love? continue to further evolve mo-mo-more!
I'm a little confused.
You already know it, love is war
What you gotta act righteous for?
Won't ya come and fight me?
Shit, Aphrodite was supposed to only wanna be adored
"You can ditch your world. Cuz I'm all you need."
With those wild words, I fall to my knees.
In the end, the reason isn't hard to see
Understanding "love," it just ain't for me
たまらなくなるほど
To the point it's unbearable,
求めて離さないで
Reach for me and don't let go.
キスじゃ足りなくて
A kiss isn't enough,
いっそ殺して
Just kill me instead.
Predilection
あなたを手に掛けて
Lay my hands on you
Infatuation
呼吸さえ止めて
Even stopping your breath
Dedication
まだまだ
Not yet, not yet
Addiction
してまたたった一口で「終わり」
And again, it's the 'end' in just one mouthful.
Predilection
さあさあ口をうけて
Now, now, open your mouth
Infatuation
そのまま飲み込んで
And swallow it just like that
Dedication
すぐさま
Immediately
Addiction
サヨナラ真っ赤、吐き出して 息が止まるのよ今
Goodbye bright red, spit it out. My breath is stopping now.
愛して愛して愛して
Love me, love me, love me
はるか遠い遠い昔　巻かれた首輪
A long, long time ago, a collar was placed.
人が欲しい　人が欲しいと　叫ぶ呪いの首輪
A cursed collar that screams for people, for people.
怒らないで　見捨てないで　どこも行かないで
Don't be angry, don't abandon me, don't go anywhere.
強く締める　吐くまで締める　人がいない　いないと
Tighten it hard, until I vomit. There's no one, no one.
いい成績でしょ
I have good grades, right?
ねえ　ねえ　いい子でしょ
Hey, hey, I'm a good child, right?
かわいい子でしょ
I'm a cute child, right?
ねえ　ねえ　いい子でしょ
Hey, hey, I'm a good child, right?
苦しいねえ
It's painful, isn't it?
愛して　愛して　愛して
Love me, love me, love me,
もっともっと 愛して 愛して
More and more. Love me, love me.
狂おしいほどに
To the point of madness.
苦しい　苦しい
It's painful, it's painful.
呪縛を　解いて　解いて　ねえ
The curse... unravel it, unravel it, hey.
止められない
It can't be stopped.
嗚呼
Aah
身体　身体　太く成っても　小さい首輪
Body, body, even if it grows big, the collar is small.
苦しくなる　足りなく成る　人が　人が　足りない
It becomes painful, it becomes insufficient. People, people are not enough.
クラスの誰にも負けない　キレイな子でしょう
I'm a beautiful child who won't lose to anyone in class, right?
あの娘よりも　どの娘よりも
More than that girl, more than any girl,
誰も彼も　私を見てよ
Everyone, look at me.
体育館裏　あなたに告白を
Behind the gym, I'll confess to you.
望みたいでしょ
It's what you want, isn't it?
あなたが好きなの
I like you.
汚いあなたが
The filthy you.
愛して　愛して　愛して　全部あげる
Love me, love me, love me, I'll give you everything.
あなたに　あなたに　全部背負って貰うよ
To you, to you, I'll have you carry everything.
足りない　あなたが　足りない
Not enough, you are not enough.
離さないよ 嗚呼
I won't let go, ah
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと
Love me, love me, love me, more and more
愛して 愛して 狂おしいほどに
Love me, love me, until it's maddening
苦しい 離さない
It hurts, I won't let go
苦しい もっともっと
It hurts, more and more
ねえ
Hey
幸せの
Of happiness
幸せの 嗚呼
Of happiness, ah
あたしが愛を語るのなら
If I were to speak of love,
その眼には如何、映る？
how would it look in your eyes?
詞は有り余るばかり
Words are more than enough,
無垢の音が流れてく
the sound of innocence flows on.
あなたが愛にまみれるまで
Until you are covered in love,
その色は幻だ
that color is an illusion.
ひとりぼっち 音に呑まれれば
If you're all alone and swallowed by sound,
全世界共通の快楽さ
it's a pleasure common to the whole world.
アンノウン・マザーグース 作詞：wowaka 作曲：wowaka
Unknown Mother Goose | Lyrics: wowaka | Composition: wowaka
つまらない 呆然に溺れる 暮らしたれもが彼をなぞる
Drowning in a dull daze, everyone living traces after him.
繰り返す使い回しの歌に また耳を塞いだ
I covered my ears again to the repetitive, reused songs.
あなたが愛を語るのなら それを答えとするの？
If you were to speak of love, would you make that the answer?
目をつぶったふりをしてるなら
If you're pretending to have your eyes closed,
この曲で醒ましてくれ
then wake me up with this song.
誰も知らぬ物語 思うばかり
Thinking only of a story no one knows.
壊れそうなくらいに 抱き締めて泣き踊った
I held on so tight it felt like I'd break, and danced while crying.
見境無い感情論 許されるのならば
If such indiscriminate emotionalism could be forgiven...
泣き出すことすらできないまま 飲み込んでった
Unable to even burst into tears, I just swallowed it down.
張り裂けてしまいそうな心があるってこと、叫ばせて！
Let me scream that I have a heart that feels like it's about to burst!
世界があたしを拒んでも 今、
Even if the world rejects me, now,
愛の唄 歌わせてくれないか
won't you let me sing a song of love?
もう一回 誰も知らないその想い
One more time, those feelings that no one knows...
この声に預けてみてもいいか
...can I entrust them to this voice?
あなたには僕が見えるか？
Can you see me?
ガラクタばかり 投げつけられてきたその背中
That back that's had nothing but junk thrown at it.
それでも好きと言えたら
If I could still say I love it,
それでも好きを願えたら
if I could still wish for love,
ああ、あたしの全部に その意味はあると
ah, that there's meaning in all of me.
ねえ、愛を語るのなら 今その胸には誰がいる
Hey, if you're speaking of love, who's in your heart right now?
こころの箱を抉じ開けて さあ、生き写しのあなた見せて？
Pry open the box of your heart and show me the spitting image of yourself.
あたしが愛にまみれるのなら 今その色は何色だ
If I'm to be covered in love, what color is it now?
孤独なんて記号では収まらない 心臓を抱えて生きてきたんだ！
I've lived my life clutching a heart that can't be contained by a label like 'lonely'!
ドッペルもどきが 其処いらに溢れた
Doppelganger-wannabes were overflowing all over the place.
挙句の果ての今日 ライラライライ
At the end of it all, today, lai-la-lai-lai.
心失きそれを 生み出した奴等は
The ones who gave birth to that heartless thing...
見切りをつけてもう バイバイバイバイ
I've given up on them already, bye-bye-bye-bye.
残されたあたしが この場所で今でも
The me that was left behind, even now in this place...
涙を堪えてるの 如何して 如何して
Why am I holding back tears? Why? Why?
あたしは知ってるわ この場所はいつでも
I know that this place is always...
あなたに守られてきたってこと！
...the fact that I've been protected by you!
痛みなどあまりにも慣れてしまった
I've grown far too used to things like pain.
何千回と巡らせ続けた 喜怒哀楽
The emotions I've let circulate thousands of times.
失えない喜びがこの世界にあるならば
If there's a joy in this world that can't be lost,
手放すことすら出来ない 哀しみさえあたしは
then even the sadness that I can't even let go of, I...
この心の 中つまはじきに してしまうのか？ それは、いやだ！
...will I end up ostracizing it within this heart? I don't want that!
どうやって この世界を愛せるかな
How can I love this world?
いつだって 転がり続けるんだろう
I'll always just keep on rolling, won't I?
ねえ、いっそ 誰も気づかないその想い
Hey, rather, those feelings that no one notices...
この唄で 明かしてみようと思うんだよ
...I think I'll try to reveal them with this song.
あなたなら何を願うか
What would you wish for?
あなたなら何を望むか
What would you desire?
軋んだ心が 誰より今を生きてるの
My creaking heart is living for the now more than anyone.
あなたには僕が見えるか？
Can you see me?
それ、あたしの行く末を照らす 灯なんだろう？
That's the light that illuminates my future, isn't it?
ねぇ、あしたを叫ぶのなら あたしはここにいるよ
Hey, if you shout for tomorrow, I'm right here
ことばが余りあまれどなお、この夢はつづいてく
Even if words overflow, this dream continues
あたしがあいをかたるのなら そのすべてはこのうただ
If I talk about love, it's all in this song
だれも知らないこのものがたり また口ずさんでしまったみたいだ
This story that no one knows, it seems I've started humming it again
握ったメッセージ that's rising hope
Grasped message, that's rising hope
揺るがない世界 非情な現状 続く壁は何重層？
Unwavering world, heartless reality, how many layers are the continuing walls?
イメージ通りなんかいかないし 静かに騒ぎだした本能
It doesn't go as imagined, and my instincts have quietly started to stir
迷路みたい 行き止まりなんだ もう思考はディストーション
Like a maze, it's a dead end, my thoughts are already distorted
容赦ないね いつの間に 見失ったルート、暴れだす
Relentless, isn't it? Before I knew it, I lost the route, starting to run wild
(pay attention!)
Hey what is it?
(watch your step now!)
常識なんか要らない
I don't need common sense
(are you serious!?)
no no no, don't worry 1,2,3
吹き返す 心臓のリズム
Breathing back, the rhythm of the heart
視界まだ眩んでる それでも行かなくちゃ
Visibility is still blurred, but I still have to go
キミが信じてる僕を 裏切るわけにいかない
I can't betray the 'me' that you believe in
強くクラクションが鳴る
A loud horn sounds
孤独なまま時が経ったって 逃げる事覚えたって
Even if time passed while being lonely, even if I learned how to run away
新しい今日が来ちゃうけど
A new today will still come
(feeling bad magic?)
この願い 例え魔法が無くなったって 叶えなきゃ、誓った
This wish, even if magic is gone, I have to fulfill it, I swore
僕はキミと まだ見ぬ未来 あるんだよ 泣きそうでも
I have a future with you that we haven't seen yet, even if I'm about to cry
悔しくても止まっていられない
Even if it's frustrating, I can't stay stopped
握ったメッセージ that's rising hope
Grasped message, that's rising hope
rising hope yeah
デモ・ケドnonstepでガンガン迫るhard way
But-however, the hard way approaches relentlessly and nonstop
(where's the solution!?)
打ちのめされても get up!
Even if you're knocked down, get up!
(and hurry up!)
そんな損な時間ならすぐさまゴミ箱
If it's such a wasteful time, put it in the trash right away
後悔なんて塵埃同然 さあ 2 step OK shouting OK 欲張りあそばせ
Regrets are just like dust. Now, 2 step OK, shouting OK, be as greedy as you like
可否も賛否も全部僕のもの 飛ばせ 心臓のアルゴリズム
Whether it's right or wrong, approval or disapproval, it's all mine. Let it fly, the algorithm of the heart
ほら 守りたいんだって 僕の声が伝播した
See, 'I want to protect you,' my voice has propagated
異論反論は許すと この想いは不用意に科学できないでしょう？
Allowing objections and counterarguments, this feeling cannot be easily explained by science, right?
聞いてよ 辿り着いた正解 言わなくちゃ
Listen, the answer I arrived at, I have to say it
キミがくれる想いの全部を信じていける
I can believe in all the feelings you give me
それが嘘かどうかなんて わからなくてもいい
It doesn't matter if it's a lie or not
誰かが示す見本ってなんだっけ 普通の愛って何だっけ
What was that example someone showed? What was 'normal love' again?
僕は今日も僕に問いかける
I ask myself again today
問いかける度 手に入れるのは 変わらない真実
Every time I ask, what I get is the unchanging truth
「僕は要らない まだ見たい未来があるから」
'I don't need it, because there's a future I still want to see'
孤独なんかは消えて無くなって 逃げる事嫌になって
Solitude disappears and is gone, I grew to hate running away
新しい今日を探すんだよ
I'm searching for a new today
(feeling bad magic?)
この願い 例え魔法が無くなったって 叶えなきゃ、誓った
This wish, even if magic is gone, I have to fulfill it, I swore
僕とキミで 創れる未来ならもう近い
The future we can create together is already near
僕の右手 キミの左手 そっと繋いで
My right hand, your left hand, gently holding them
握ったメッセージ that's rising hope
Grasped message, that's rising hope
離さないから that's rising hope
I won't let go, that's rising hope
rising hope
歌を歌うことを、諦めようと思ったときがありました。
There was a time when I thought about giving up on singing.
思ったように歌えず、苦しい時もたくさんあります。
There are many painful times when I can't sing as I'd like.
でも、
But,
それでも、
Even so,
僕が歌を歌うのは、
The reason I sing is...
みんなが応援してくれるからです。
...because everyone supports me.
これから先も頑張っていくから、
I'll keep doing my best from now on, too,
ずっとそばで見守っていてください。
so please keep watching over me by my side.
それでは、聞いてください。
Now, please listen.
ファンサ。
Fansa.
好きになって！もっと！
Love me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもった投げキッスで”
I'll pay you back "with a blow kiss full of love"
気のせいじゃない　目は合ってるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting
ハート作って恋しちゃってください！
Make a heart and please fall in love!
やれること何でもします
I'll do whatever I can
NG無しで体当たり挑戦
Taking on challenges without saying no
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ「ふざけんな」…誰より分かってるし
Found anti-comments through ego-searching "Don't mess around"... I know better than anyone
でも大丈夫ここに立てばみんながいる
But it's okay, if I stand here, everyone is here
行くよ！
Here we go!
好きになって！もっと！
Love me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもった投げキッスで”
I'll pay you back "with a blow kiss full of love"
虜にする！もっと！
I'll captivate you! More!
夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでって　愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Enjoy yourself, a special night full of love
ファンサしちゃうぞ（＞ω＜）
I'm gonna give you some fan service (>ω<)
お手紙も書いてください！
Please write me letters too!
何度も読んで宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and cherish them
スキャンダルまだ早いけど
Scandals are still too early, but...
裏切りません！宣言しときます（・ω・）b
I won't betray you! I'm declaring it now (・ω・)b
嫉妬、嫌がらせには負けない　「ふざけんな」実力で勝ってやる
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment "Don't mess around", I'll win with my talent
だから辞めない　負けず嫌い私はいる
So I won't quit, I'm here because I hate to lose
行くよ！
Here we go!
拳上げて！もっと！
Raise your fists! More!
汗をかいて！もっと！
Work up a sweat! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもったかなたビームで”
I'll pay you back "with a Kanata Beam full of love"
大歓声！もっと！
A huge cheer! More!
まだまだ！ねぇ？もっと！
Not yet! Hey? More!
受け止めてね　愛のこもったわがままソング
Please take it, a selfish song full of love
ファンサしちゃうぞ！
I'm gonna give you some fan service!
はぁ…終わりが近づく　寂しいね
Ah... the end is near, it's sad, isn't it?
楽しいのに泣きそうだよ
Even though it's fun, I feel like crying
次も次もまた会えるよね？
We can meet again next time, and the time after that, right?
約束！
Promise!
優しさに溢れている言葉も　心無い誰かの言葉さえも
Words overflowing with kindness, even the heartless words of someone
必要なんだ必要なんだ強くなろう
They're all necessary, they're all necessary, let's become strong
好きに叫べ！もっと！
Shout as you like! More!
楽しんじゃえ！もっと！
Just enjoy it! More!
共に歌おう（ずっと）
Let's sing together (forever)
共に歩もう（ずっと）
Let's walk together (forever)
合言葉はとびっきりの「L-O-V-E」
The password is the ultimate "L-O-V-E"
好きになって！もっと！
Love me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもった投げキッスで”
I'll pay you back "with a blow kiss full of love"
虜にする！もっと！
I'll captivate you! More!
夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでって　愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Enjoy yourself, a special night full of love
ファンサしちゃうぞ！
I'm gonna give you some fan service!
あー！みんなのおかげで、
Ah! Thanks to everyone,
天音かなた2周年迎えることができました！
Amane Kanata's 2nd anniversary is here!
本当に、本当にみんなのことが大好きだよー！
I really, really love you all!
飛んで　飛んで　舞い降りる
Flying, flying, dancing down
天使のagape
Angel's Agape
作詞：渡辺翔 作曲：渡辺翔 編曲：渡辺翔
Tenshi no Agape
Lyrics, Composition, & Arrangement: Sho Watanabe
優しく鐘の音鳴って
Gently the sound of bells rings out
永久にじゃれあいたいな
I want to play around for eternity
鳥籠いらない そんな
I don't need a birdcage, to such a...
理想に満ちた此処へ
...place filled with ideals
君を連れ出せたなら
If I could take you out there
ねぇ 羽の色も 髪の色も
Hey, the color of your wings and hair...
違ってそれぞれ綺麗
...are different and beautiful in their own way
傷付かないように包み込もう
I'll wrap you up so you don't get hurt
護ってたら護られてた
I was protecting you, but I was being protected
君へのこの讃歌
This hymn for you
ずっと届けたい
I want to send it to you forever
さあ祝福を
Now, a blessing
ファミリア 癒して 戯れ幸せ
Familia, heal me, playful happiness
寄り添い合って 辛さ全部 覆う天命で
Snuggling together, with destiny covering the pain
ファミリア 誰にも 見せない表情を
Familia, an expression I show to no one else
羽の奥からそっと 僕だけへと
Quietly from behind my wings, just for me
飛んで 飛んで 舞い降りる天使のagape
Fly, fly, the descending angel's agape
弱さを見せてもいいよ
It's okay to show your weakness
辛さ押し付けていいよ
It's okay to push your pain onto me
たとえ離れたとしても 空からの使いだから
Even if we're apart, I'm a messenger from the sky
君を見守れるんだ
So I can watch over you
ねぇ 出会えたこと 笑えたこと その先で報われて
Hey, that we met and laughed, may we be rewarded
幸せさらに重ね合わそう
Let's layer more happiness together
大切なものがある聖域 役目を刻み込んで
Engraving our roles into this precious sanctuary
きっと誰にも きっと譲らない
Surely to no one, surely I won't give it up
白く広げ
Spreading white
白く羽ばたく
Flapping white wings
白く 白く
White, white...
ファミリア 癒して 戯れ幸せ
Familia, heal me, playful happiness
寄り添い合って 辛さ全部 覆う天命で
Snuggling together, with destiny covering the pain
ファミリア 誰にも 見せない表情を
Familia, an expression I show to no one else
羽の奥からそっと 僕だけへと
Quietly from behind my wings, just for me
飛んで 飛んで 舞い降りる天使のagape
Fly, fly, the descending angel's agape
いつでもここにいるよ
I'll always be here
特者生存ワンダラダー！！
作詞：田淵智也 作曲：田淵智也
Tokusha Seizon Wonder-ladder!!
Lyrics & Composition: Tomoya Tabuchi
なぬっ？ビシッ おりゃっ！バシッ
What? Smacking! Take that! Thump!
ツッコミも冴えて 本日快晴
Sharp retorts and clear skies today
ざわっ ボロッ むむっ パキッ
Murmuring, crumbling, hmmm, snapping
手にする全部 It's mine! くれくれ
Everything I get is mine! Gimme gimme
適度にがんばろっか そんなんだっていいけどさ
Let's work hard in moderation, that's fine too
必死にがんばろっか それが僕らしいよな
Let's work hard desperately, that's more like me
ダサすぎ じゃねえんだわ！そんで貧乏性 じゃねえんだわ！
It's not too uncool! And it's not being stingy!
運ん万事がバッチリイケてるに決まってる！
Everything's bound to be perfectly cool!
(are you?) かなたちゃん☆
(Are you?) Kanata-chan☆
どどん前進上等！ちゃんと歓迎して
Full speed ahead! Welcome me properly
高まれ海空創造！ちゃんと驚嘆して
Rise up, creation of sea and sky! Be amazed properly
興奮しよう
Let's get excited
僕が言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん
Because I say so, because I'll really do it
現実超えちゃう未来 アーイ！
A future that transcends reality, aye!
弱点も平気 スイッチでランチャー！
Weaknesses are fine, switch on the launcher!
すなわち特者生存ワンダランDAY 楽しもう！
That is, the privileged survival Wonderland DAY, let's enjoy!
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダー！！ 楽しもう
Which is to say, it's a "Special-Person-Survival Wonderland"!! Let's enjoy it!
面白がれること探したまえ over?
Please look for something interesting, over?
返事聞かせてくれ！
Let me hear your reply!
右左なんかじゃない
It's not about right or left
決めつけて一直線
Decide and go straight ahead
つまり企んだら発射オーライだ！
In other words, if you've got a plan, blast off—all right!
ワクワクさせるぜー！
I'm gonna make it exciting!
みんな、2年目に突入しましたが
Everyone, I've entered my second year, but...
まだ楽器の結婚は立ち直っていません！
I still haven't recovered from the "instrument marriage"!
2年目の目標は、ハイ・アップがついたオリジナル曲を出すこと！
My goal for the second year is to release an original song with "High Up"!
「何だよそんなこと言っちゃダメだ、おバカ」
"What are you saying? You shouldn't say such things, you dummy."
「うわ〜すごい！ ありがと〜」
"Wow, amazing! Thank you~"
日々これ騒然で go my way!
Every day is tumultuous, so go my way!
虎視眈々でいたいんだもん だって意気ガンガンがいいんだもん
I want to keep a sharp eye out, because I want to be full of spirit
全方位にガッツリ アンテナ張っていなくちゃ！
I've got to keep my antennae fully up in all directions!
いつでも心はちゃんと忠誠でいたいな
I always want my heart to be properly loyal
好奇心は絶えず熱心でいたいなって
I want my curiosity to be constantly enthusiastic
言い聞かせるんだ 調子に乗ったら
I'll tell myself that if I get carried away
すぐ飽きられちゃうから あー！
People will soon get tired of me!
タイトロープもどんとこいでっせ
Bring on the tightrope walk too
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダー！！
Which is to say, it's a "Special-Person-Survival Wonderland"!!
しがみつけ
Hold on tight!
“努力とは最後まで諦めないこと”
“Effort means not giving up until the very end”
メモっておいて！
Take a note of that!
ホントは baby 自信なんかがないよ
To be honest, baby, I have no confidence
ホントは baby 不安ばっかで泣きそうだ
To be honest, baby, I'm full of anxiety and about to cry
でもね baby 挫けないって決めたの
But you see, baby, I've decided not to give up
だから baby 挑戦したいよ 未開の天地 無限のフィールドで！
So, baby, I want to take on the challenge in uncharted territory, an infinite field!
行くぞ！
Here I go!
前進上等！ ちゃんと歓迎して 高まれ
Moving forward is fine! Please welcome me properly and get pumped up
海空創造 ちゃんと驚喜して 興奮しよう
Creating sea and sky, let's be properly overjoyed and get excited
僕が言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん
Because I say so, I'm really going to do it
現実超えろ未来 あー！
Surpass reality, the future, ah!
弱点も平気 シンデレラじゃない
I'm fine with weaknesses, I'm no Cinderella
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダー！！
Which is to say, it's a "Special-Person-Survival Wonderland"!!
楽しもう
Let's enjoy it!
面白がれること探し放題でっせ
There are endless interesting things to find
無限のフィールドで
In an infinite field
パニックしなくてもいけ
You don't have to panic
ど真ん中一直線
Go straight through the middle
つまりこれが僕の答えなんだ
In short, this is my answer
胸を張れ！ 今を生きるぞその意味を
Hold your head high! Live in the now, and its meaning
明くる日も明くる日も確かめ進め！
Day after day, confirm it and move forward!
行くぞ！
Here I go!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
天音かなた2周年記念LIVE「リベンジ」、どうだったでしょうか？
Amane Kanata 2nd Anniversary LIVE "Revenge," how was it?
みんなにね、最後まで見てくれたみんなにアンケートを取りたいと思います。
To everyone, to everyone who watched until the end, I'd like to take a survey.
本日一番印象に残った曲はどれだったでしょうか？
Which song left the strongest impression on you today?
こちらセトリになっているんですが
Here is the setlist...
1とか2とか3とか、曲名の前に書いてある数字を
Please type the number written before the song title, like 1, 2, or 3...
大文字でも小文字でもOKなので、コメントに打ってくれると
Either uppercase or lowercase is fine, if you type it in the comments...
勝手に機械が集計いたします。
The system will automatically tally them.
これの集計結果は、配信後に僕のTwitterアカウントで発表したいと思います。
I'll announce the results on my Twitter account after the stream.
みんなありがとうございます！
Thank you all so much!
そして！ ダダダダン！ ドドン！
And then! *Drumroll*! Ta-da!
活動2周年記念グッズ！ ポンポンポン！ パフパフ！
2nd Anniversary Commemorative Goods! *Fanfare*!
こちらもね、今回出させていただきます。
I'll be releasing these this time as well.
直筆サインも書くので、ぜひぜひチェックしてみてください。
I'll also be signing them, so please do check them out.
まずは紹介していきたいと思います。
First, let me introduce them.
あ、えーと、アンケートの方はね、引き続き集計中ですので
Oh, also, the survey is still being tallied, so...
数字ね、打っていただけると嬉しいです。
...I'd be happy if you'd keep typing the numbers.
はい、まずはラバーマット。にもし先生に描いていただきました。可愛い。
Okay, first is the rubber mat. It was drawn by Nimoshi-sensei. It's cute.
そして手帳型マルチスマホケース。
And the notebook-style multi-smartphone case.
スマホケースみんな欲しいって言ってたので作ったぞと。
Everyone said they wanted a smartphone case, so I made one.
そして天音かなた 1st Single「特者生存ワンダラダー！！」
And Amane Kanata 1st Single "Tokusha Seizon Wonderland-da!!"
CDとしてね、今回グッズに付いて参ります。
This time, it will be included in the goods as a CD.
こちら2曲目「Stardust Song」をかなたがソロバージョンで新しく収録しておりますので
The second track, "Stardust Song," is a new solo recording by Kanata...
こちらもぜひチェックしてください。
...so please check that out too.
そして2nd Singleの「天使のagape」。
And the 2nd Single, "Tenshi no Agape."
こちらも「BLUE CLAPPER」をカバーさせていただきましたので
I also covered "BLUE CLAPPER" for this...
ぜひぜひそっちもチェックしてほしいなと思います。
...so I'd really like you to check that out as well.
ということでね、皆さん本当にたくさんありがとうございます。
With that, thank you all so much.
コメントもありがとう。
Thank you for the comments too.
そしてそしてこちらね、活動2周年記念の商品構成
And here's the lineup for the 2nd Anniversary goods...
構成になっております。
...this is the lineup.
ボイスも取りました。なんか罵倒系のボイスを撮ったので
I also recorded voices. I recorded some "abusive" type voices, so...
ぜひそちらもチェックしてみてください、ドMの皆さんは。はい。
...for you masochists out there, please check them out. Yes.
そして「天使のagape」ですが、こちら楽曲の配信は昨日の夜から始まっておりますので
As for "Tenshi no Agape," it's been available for streaming since last night...
「天使のagape」
天音かなた オリジナル曲 第二弾
"Angel's Agape"
Amane Kanata 2nd Original Song
ぜひぜひチェックしてみてください。
Please be sure to check it out.
そしてこのあとすぐ、22時15分からアニメMVが投稿されるので、
And right after this, from 22:15, an anime MV will be posted,
かなたのチャンネルにそのまま居座ってください。
so please stay right here on Kanata's channel.
ぜひぜひチェックしてみてね、ということで、
Be sure to check it out! And so,
皆さん今回は本当に本当にありがとうございました。
everyone, thank you so very, very much for today.
天音かなた2周年、そして3周目に入りまして、
Amane Kanata's 2nd anniversary, and entering the 3rd year...
3年目か、3年目に入りまして、
...I mean the 3rd year, entering the 3rd year,
これからも元気いっぱい頑張っていきたいと思います。
I'll continue to do my best with all my energy.
それでは、おつかなたでした！
And with that, Otsukanata!
バイバイ！ありがとう！
Bye-bye! Thank you!
REVENGE
Amane Kanata 2nd Anniversary LIVE